Register of the Eric Hoffer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1934-1983
  - "Changes," Cavalier, 1966 August (Box-folder 60: 9)
  - "Comments on the Human Condition," Harper's, 1966 November (Box-folder 60: 10)
  - The Temper of Our Time, 1967
    - Notes (Box-folder 60: 11)
    - Holograph drafts (Box-folder 60: 12-14)
    - Holograph and typescript draft (Box-folder 60: 15)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - Proofs (Box-folder 61: 2-4)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 61: 5)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 61: 6-7)
    - Reprint of excerpt, The Rotarian, 1967 June (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - Anthologies containing excerpts from The Temper of Our Time
      - Hulon Willis, ed., Basic Usage, Vocabulary, and Composition, 1971 (Box-folder 62: 2)
      - Ray Kytle, ed., Confrontation: Issues of the 70s, 1971 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - "Man, Play and Creativity," Think, 1967 September-October
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 62: 4)
    - Spanish translation published in Facetas, 1968 (Box-folder 62: 5)
      No.1. Printed copy
    - Reprint, The Blade Sunday Magazine, 1968 April 7 (Box-folder 62: 6)
      Includes correspondence
    - Japanese translation published in Japan-America Forum, 1968 June (Box-folder 62: 7)
    - Reprint, Lantern, 1968 June (Box-folder 62: 8)
  - "Eric Hoffer: The Passionate State of Mind," television interview with Eric Sevareid, CBS, 1967 September 19
    - Transcript and reviews (Box-folder 62: 9)
      See also: VIDEOTAPES for copy of broadcast
    - Correspondence from viewers (Box-folder 62: 10-11)
  - "Man and Nature: The Return of Nature," speech, University of California, Davis, 1967 November (Box-folder 63: 1)
    Typescript and correspondence
  - "The Madhouse of Change," Playboy, 1968 December (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - Working and Thinking on the Waterfront, 1969
    See also: Box 77 for Japanese edition
    - Diaries used as the basis of book, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 63: 3-4)
      Holographs
    - Holograph drafts (Box-folder 63: 5-6)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 63: 7)
    - Proofs (Box-folder 64: 1-3)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 64: 4)
    - Books containing excerpts from Working and Thinking on the Waterfront, 1974
      - Gerald Kennedy, ed., My Third Reader's Notebook, 1974 (Box-folder 64: 5)
      - Bazerman, Charles, The Informed Writer, 1981 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - "The Savage Heart: A Conversation with Eric Hoffer," television interview with Eric Sevareid, CBS, 1969 January 28
    - Transcripts (Box-folder 65: 1-4)
    - Correspondence from viewers (Box-folder 65: 5-7)
  - "End of a 830,726 Mile Voyage," Detroit News, 1969 July(?) (Box-folder 65: 8)
    Holograph and printed copy
  - Statement on moon landing, New York Times, 1969 July 21 (Box-folder 65: 9)
  - "Whose Country Is America?," New York Times Magazine, 1970 November 22
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 66: 1)
      Anthologies reprinting this article
    - Donald Rude, ed., Alienation: Minority Groups, 1972 (Box-folder 66: 2)
    - Harold Full, ed., Controversy in American Education, 1972 (Box-folder 66: 3)
    - Robert Turk and Robert Kenney, eds., Selected Readings in the Social Sciences, 1973 (Box-folder 66: 4)
    - Edward P. J. Corbett, ed., The Essay: Subjects and Stances, 1974 (Box-folder 66: 5)
  - Diary entries, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 66: 6)
  - First Things, Last Things, 1971
    - Holograph drafts (Box-folder 66: 7-9)
    - Holograph drafts (Box-folder 67: 1)
    - Typescript fragment (Box-folder 67: 2)
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 67: 3-4)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 67: 5)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 67: 6)
    - Anthologies containing excerpts from First Things, Last Things
      - Louis G. Locke, William M. Gibson, George Arms, George Petty, eds., TLE Six: Options for the 1970s, 1972 (Box-folder 67: 7)
      - D. W. Cummings and John Herum, eds., Tempo: Life, Work and Leisure, 1974 (Box-folder 68: 1)
  - "Thoughts of Eric Hoffer, Including: 'Absolute Faith Corrupts Absolutely'," New York Times Magazine, 1971 April 25
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 68: 2)
    - Reprint, Reader's Digest, 1971 August (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - "A Better People," commencement address, Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 1971 May 30 (Box-folder 68: 4)
    See also: SOUND RECORDINGS for copy of speech
    Typescript.
  - "A Better People," commencement address, Michigan Technological University, Houghton, Michigan, 1971 June 12 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Speech upon receiving the Human Resources Award, Human Resources Congress, Chicago, Illinois, 1972 August 26 (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Reflections on the Human Condition, 1973
    - Reviews (Box-folder 68: 7)
    - Excerpt, "Hidden Currents that Guide Our Lives," Family Weekly, 1972 September 24 (Box-folder 68: 8)
    - Excerpt published in Alton C. Morris et al, eds., College English: The First Year, 1978 (Box-folder 68: 9)
  - "Eric Hoffer: Reflections from the Waterfront," television interview, Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1974 (Box-folder 68: 10)
    Transcript
  - "Long Live Shame!," New York Times, 1974 October 8 (Box-folder 68: 11)
  - "What We Have Lost," New York Times Magazine, 1974 October 20 (Box-folder 68: 12)
  - Unpublished anthology of articles, 1976(?) (Box-folder 69: 1)
    Holograph texts and printed selections from other works
  - In Our Time, 1976
    - Holograph drafts (Box-folder 69: 2-7)
    - Holograph and typescript draft (Box-folder 69: 8)
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 70: 1-4)
    - Editorial notes (Box-folder 70: 5)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 70: 6)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 70: 7)
    - Excerpt, "I Savor the Joy of Dull Work," Family Weekly, 1976 October 17 (Box-folder 70: 8)
  - "What America Means to Me," Reader's Digest, 1976 September (Box-folder 70: 9)
  - "Capitalism," speech, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1977 April 28
    - Holograph drafts (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 71: 2)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 71: 3)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 71: 4)
  - "The Crowded Life," television interview, PBS, 1978 January (Box-folder 71: 5)
    Correspondence from viewers
  - Speech, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1978 October(?) (Box-folder 71: 6)
  - Speech, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1978 October(?) (Box-folder 71: 7)
  - Speech, College High School, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1978 October(?) (Box-folder 71: 8)
    See also: SOUND RECORDINGS for tape of talk
  - Speech, Sooner High School, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1978 October(?) (Box-folder 71: 9)
  - "What Solzhenitsyn Said Was True," Manchester Union Leader, 1978 November 4 (Box-folder 71: 10)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - Before the Sabbath, 1979
    - Holograph fragment (Box-folder 71: 11)
    - Holgraph draft (Box-folder 71: 12)
    - Holograph draft, with some typescript pages (Box-folder 71: 13)
    - Typescript draft, with some holograph pages (Box-folder 72: 1)
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 72: 2-3)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 72: 4)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 72: 5-6)
  - "Beware the Intellectual," speech, Edison Centennial Symposium, San Francisco, California, 1979 April 4
    - Typescript (Box-folder 73: 1)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 73: 2)
    - Correspondence, program, and symposium paper by René Dumont, "From Agricultural Plenty to the Hunger of the Third World" (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - "Islam and Modernization," The American Spectator, 1980 June (Box-folder 73: 4)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence
  - Essays, 1981
    - Holograph (Box-folder 73: 5)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 73: 6)
  - "The Weak as Change Agents," The Tarrytown Letter, 1981 April (Box-folder 73: 7)
  - Between the Devil and the Dragon, 1982 (Box-folder 73: 8)
    Reviews
  - Truth Imagined, 1983
    See also: OVERSIZE MATERIALS for proofs
    - Holograph fragment (Box-folder 73: 9)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 73: 10)
    - Typescript draft (Box-folder 73: 11)
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 74: 1-4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 74: 5)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 74: 6)
  - Foreign translations of The True Believer, The Ordeal of Change, The Temper of Our Time, Working and Thinking on the Waterfront, First Things, Last Things, and In Our Time, 1965-1979 (Boxes 75-77)
- Notebooks, 1936-1981
  Originals and typed transcriptions, arranged chronologically.
  - Undated originals (Boxes 78-81)
  - Numbered and dated originals
    - No. QII, 1949 November 10 - 1950 January 9 (Box-folder 82: 1)
    - No. QIN, 1950 January 10 - March 31 (Box-folder 82: 2)
    - No. QIIN, 1950 April 1-29 (Box-folder 82: 3)
    - No. QIIIN, 1950 April 29 - June 11 (Box-folder 82: 4)
    - No. QIVN, 1950 June 11 - July 20 (Box-folder 82: 5)
    - No. QVN, 1950 July 20 - August 19 (Box-folder 82: 6)
    - No. QVI, 1950 August 20 - October 8 (Box-folder 82: 7)
    - No. QVII, 1950 October 8 – November 18 (Box-folder 82: 8)
    - No. QIII, 1950 November 19 - 1951 January 5 (Box-folder 82: 9)
    - No. QIX, 1951 January 5 - April 14 (Box-folder 82: 10)
    - No. 10, 1951 April 14 – May 22 (Box-folder 82: 11)
    - No. 11, 1951 May 22 – July 9 (Box-folder 82: 12)
    - No. 12, 1951 July 10 – September 18 (Box-folder 82: 13)
    - No. 13, 1951 September 18 – November 3 (Box-folder 82: 14)
    - No. 14, 1951 November 4-30 (Box-folder 82: 15)
    - No. 15, 1951 November 30 – December 20 (Box-folder 82: 16)
    - No. 17, 1951 December 20 - 1952 January 23 (Box-folder 83: 1)
    - No. 18, 1952 January 23 – March 20 (Box-folder 83: 2)
    - No. 19, 1952 March 20 – July 5 (Box-folder 83: 3)
    - No. 20, 1952 July 5 – September 21 (Box-folder 83: 4)
    - No. 21, 1952 September 23 – December 19 (Box-folder 83: 5)
    - No. 22, 1952 December 19 – 1953 March 5 (Box-folder 83: 6)
    - No. 23, 1953 March 7 – July 19 (Box-folder 83: 7)
    - No. 24, 1953 July 19 – September 19 (Box-folder 83: 8)
    - No. 25, 1953 September 19 – December 12 (Box-folder 83: 9)
    - No. 26, 1953 December 12 - 1954 April 27 (Box-folder 83: 10)
    - No. 27, 1954 April 27 – June 22 (Box-folder 83: 11)
    - No. 28, 1954 June 22 – October 15 (Box-folder 83: 12)
    - No. 29, 1954 October 16 - 1955 January 16 (Box-folder 83: 13)
    - No. 30, 1955 January 17 – March 13 (Box-folder 83: 14)
    - No. 31, 1955 March 14 – April 24 (Box-folder 84: 1)
    - No. 32, 1955 April 25 – June 24 (Box-folder 84: 2)
    - No. 33, 1955 June 25 – August 20 (Box-folder 84: 3)
    - No. 34, 1955 August 22 – October 25 (Box-folder 84: 4)
    - No. 35, 1955 October 25 – December 26 (Box-folder 84: 5)
    - No. 36, 1955 December 26 - 1956 February 4 (Box-folder 84: 6)
    - No. 37, 1956 February 4 – May 5 (Box-folder 84: 7)
    - No. 38, 1956 May 5 – July 17 (Box-folder 84: 8)
    - No. 39, 1956 July 17 – October 14 (Box-folder 84: 9)
    - No. 40, 1956 October 1 – December 31 (Box-folder 84: 10)
    - No. 41, 1956 December 31 - 1957 April 1 (Box-folder 84: 11)
    - No. 42, 1957 April 1 – June 8 (Box-folder 84: 12)
    - No. 43, 1957 June 8 – July 15 (Box-folder 84: 13)
    - No. 44, 1957 July 15 – September 28 (Box-folder 84: 14)
    - No. 45, 1957 September 28 – December 29 (Box-folder 85: 1)
    - No. 46, 1957 December 29 - 1958 April (Box-folder 85: 2)
    - No. 47, 1958 April – July 4 (Box-folder 85: 3)
    - No. 48, 1958 July 5 – October (Box-folder 85: 4)
    - No. 49, 1958 October – December (Box-folder 85: 5)
    - No. 50, 1959 January – March (Box-folder 85: 6)
    - No. 51, 1959 April – May 9 (Box-folder 85: 7)
    - No. 52, 1959 May 9 – July 5 (Box-folder 85: 8)
    - No. 53, 1959 July 5 – September 11 (Box-folder 85: 9)
    - No. 54, 1959 September 12 – November 23 (Box-folder 85: 10)
    - No. 55, 1959 November 23 - 1960 February 6 (Box-folder 85: 11)
    - No. 56, 1960 February 6 – May 31 (Box-folder 85: 12)
    - No. 57, 1960 June 13 – July 18 (Box-folder 85: 13)
    - No. 58, 1960 July 18 – September 1 (Box-folder 85: 14)
    - No. 59, 1960 September 2 – October 22 (Box-folder 85: 15)
    - No. 60, 1960 October 23 - 1961 February 26 (Box-folder 85: 16)
    - No. 61, 1961 February 27 – June 16 (Box-folder 85: 17)
    - No. 61A, 1961 June 17 – July 16 (Box-folder 85: 18)
    - No. 62, 1961 June 25 – September 4 (Box-folder 86: 1)
    - No. 63, 1961 September 4 – October 7 (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - No. 64, 1961 October 8 – November 30 (Box-folder 86: 3)
    - No. 65, 1961 November 30 - 1962 March 6 (Box-folder 86: 4)
    - No. 66, 1962 March 6 – May 8 (Box-folder 86: 5)
    - No. 67, 1962 May 9 – June 18 (Box-folder 86: 6)
    - No. 68, 1962 June 18 - September 29 (Box-folder 86: 7)
    - No. 69, 1962 October-November (Box-folder 86: 8)
    - No. 70, 1962 December 6 - 1963 March (Box-folder 86: 9)
    - No. 71, 1963 March 21 – May 13 (Box-folder 86: 10)
    - No. 72, 1963 May 13 – June 11 (Box-folder 86: 11)
    - No. 73, 1963 June 11 – August 13 (Box-folder 86: 12)
    - No. 74, 1963 August 13 – December 5 (Box-folder 86: 13)
    - No. 75, 1963 December 5 - 1964 January 1 (Box-folder 86: 14)
    - No. 76, 1964 January 6 – February 10 (Box-folder 86: 15)
    - No. 77, 1964 February 10 – June 7 (Box-folder 86: 16)
    - No. 78, 1964 June 7 – September 1 (Box-folder 86: 17)
    - No. 79, 1964 September 1 – November 3 (Box-folder 86: 18)
    - No. 80, 1964 November 3 – December 17 (Box-folder 86: 19)
    - No. 81, 1964 December 17 - 1965 January 26 (Box-folder 87: 1)
    - No. 82, 1965 January 27 – March 9 (Box-folder 87: 2)
    - No. 83, 1965 March 9 – April 20 (Box-folder 87: 3)
    - No. 84, 1965 April 20 – May 26 (Box-folder 87: 4)
    - No. 85, 1965 May 26 – June 27 (Box-folder 87: 5)
    - No. 86, 1965 June 27 – October 18 (Box-folder 87: 6)
    - No. 87, 1965 October 18 – December 26 (Box-folder 87: 7)
    - No. 88, 1965 December 26 - 1966 March 9 (Box-folder 87: 8)
    - No. 89, 1966 March 9 – June 6 (Box-folder 87: 9)
    - No. 90, 1966 June 6 – August 6 (Box-folder 87: 10)
    - No. 91, 1966 August 7 – November 25 (Box-folder 87: 11)
    - No. 92, 1966 November 25 - 1967 April 7 (Box-folder 87 :12)
    - No. 93, 1967 April 7 – July 7 (Box-folder 87: 13)
    - No. 94, 1967 July 8 – August 11 (Box-folder 87: 14)
    - No. 95, 1967 August 11 – October 28 (Box-folder 87: 15)
    - No. 96, 1967 October 28 - 1968 March 6 (Box-folder 87: 16)
    - No. 97, 1968 March 6 – July 20 (Box-folder 88: 1)
    - No. 98, 1968 July 2 – October 22 (Box-folder 88: 2)
    - No. 99, 1968 October 23 - 1969 January 22 (Box-folder 88: 3)
    - No. 100, 1969 January 22 – April 28 (Box-folder 88: 4)
    - No. 101, 1969 April 28 – June 28 (Box-folder 88: 5)
    - No. 102, 1969 June 28 – September 22 (Box-folder 88: 6)
    - No. 103, 1969 September 22 – November 22 (Box-folder 88: 7)
    - No. 104, 1969 November 23 - 1970 February 20 (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - No. 105, 1970 February 19 – May 14 (Box-folder 88: 9)
    - No. 106, 1970 May 14 – September 14 (Box-folder 88: 10)
    - No. 107, 1970 September 14 – December 21 (Box-folder 88: 11)
    - No. 108, 1970 December 22 - 1971 April 2 (Box-folder 88: 12)
    - No. 109, 1971 April 2 – June 17 (Box-folder 88: 13)
    - No. 110, 1971 June 18 – October 5 (Box-folder 88: 14)
    - No. 111, 1971 October 5 - 1972 January 25 (Box-folder 88: 15)
    - No. 112, 1972 January 25 – April 26 (Box-folder 89: 1)
    - No. 113, 1972 April 26 – July 6 (Box-folder 89: 2)
    - No. 114, 1972 July 7 – September 15 (Box-folder 89: 3)
    - No. 115, 1972 September 15 – December 13 (Box-folder 89: 4)
    - No. 116, 1972 December 13 - 1973 February 27 (Box-folder 89: 5)
    - No. 117, 1973 February 27 – May 7 (Box-folder 89: 6)
    - No. 118, 1973 May 7 – July 9 (Box-folder 89: 7)
    - No. 119, 1973 July 9 – October 10 (Box-folder 89: 8)
    - No. 120, 1973 October 10 – 1974 March 15 (Box-folder 89: 9)
    - No. 121, 1974 March 15 – July 11 (Box-folder 89: 10)
    - No. 122, 1974 July 11 – November 1 (Box-folder 89: 11)
    - No. 123, 1974 November 7 – 1975 January 30 (Box-folder 89: 12)
    - [No. 124, missing]
    - No. 125, 1975 September 26 – November 23 (Box-folder 89: 13)
    - No. 126, 1975 November 23 - 1976 May 8 (Box-folder 89: 14)
    - No. 127, 1976 May 8 – December 31 (Box-folder 90: 1)
    - No. 128, 1976 December 31 – 1977 March 26 (Box-folder 90: 2)
    - No. 129, 1977 March 27 – May 29 (Box-folder 90: 3)
    - No. 130, 1977 May 29 – July 5 (Box-folder 90: 4)
    - No. 131, 1977 July 5 (Box-folder 90: 5)
  - Typed transcriptions of numbered and dated originals
    For dates, see those for originals above
    Notebook numbers correspond to the originals. Page numbers refer to typescript, which does not fully reproduce the contents of the originals.
    - No. QIN, pp. 1-22 (Box-folder 90: 6)
    - No. QIIN, pp. 23-40 (Box-folder 90: 7)
    - No. QIIIN, pp. 41-54 (Box-folder 90: 8)
    - No. QIVN, pp. 55-78 (Box-folder 90: 9)
    - No. QVN, pp. 79-100 (Box-folder 90: 10)
    - No. QVI, pp. 101-124 (Box-folder 90: 11)
    - No. QVII, pp. 125-147 (Box-folder 90: 12)
    - No. QVIII, pp. 148-170 (Box-folder 90: 13)
    - No. QIX, pp. 171-203 (Box-folder 90: 14)
    - No. 10, pp. 204-224 (Box-folder 90: 15)
    - No. 11, pp. 225-249 (Box-folder 90: 16)
    - No. 12, pp. 250-273 (Box-folder 90: 17)
    - No. 13, pp. 274-296 (Box-folder 90: 18)
    - No. 14, pp. 297-318 (Box-folder 90: 19)
    - No. 15, pp. 319-344 (Box-folder 90: 20)
    - No. 16, pp. 345-361 (Box-folder 90: 21)
    - No. 17, pp. 362-391 (Box-folder 90: 22)
    - No. 18, pp. 392-415 (Box-folder 90: 23)
    - No. 19, pp. 416-441 (Box-folder 91: 1)
    - No. 20, pp. 442-467 (Box-folder 91: 2)
    - No. 21, pp. 468-489 (Box-folder 91: 3)
    - No. 22, pp. 490-510 (Box-folder 91: 4)
    - No. 23, pp. 511-542 (Box-folder 91: 5)
    - No. 24, pp. 543-558 (Box-folder 91: 6)
    - No. 25, pp. 559-581 (Box-folder 91: 7)
    - No. 26, pp. 582-608 (Box-folder 91: 8)
    - No. 27, pp. 609-628 (Box-folder 91: 9)
    - No. 28, pp. 629-647 (Box-folder 91: 10)
    - No. 29, pp. 648-671 (Box-folder 91: 11)
    - No. 30, pp. 672-707 (Box-folder 91: 12)
    - No. 31, pp. 708-731 (Box-folder 91: 13)
    - No. 32, pp. 732-751 (Box-folder 91: 14)
    - No. 33, pp. 752-776 (Box-folder 91: 15)
    - No. 34, pp. 777-797 (Box-folder 91: 16)
    - No. 35, pp. 798-814 (Box-folder 91: 17)
    - No. 36, pp. 815-829 (Box-folder 91: 18)
    - No. 37, pp. 830-858 (Box-folder 91: 19)
    - No. 38, pp. 859-886 (Box-folder 91: 20)
    - No. 39, pp. 887-904 (Box-folder 91: 21)
    - No. 40, pp. 905-932 (Box-folder 91: 22)
    - No. 41, pp. 933-951 (Box-folder 91: 23)
    - No. 42, pp. 952-974 (Box-folder 91: 24)
    - No. 43, pp. 975-989 (Box-folder 91: 25)
    - No. 44, pp. 990-1025 (Box-folder 92: 1)
    - No. 45, pp. 1026-1043 (Box-folder 92: 2)
    - No. 46, pp. 1044-1061 (Box-folder 92: 3)
    - No. 47, pp. 1062-1089 (Box-folder 92: 4)
    - No. 48, pp. 1090-1110 (Box-folder 92: 5)
    - No. 49, pp. 1111-1136 (Box-folder 92: 6)
    - No. 50, pp. 1137-1161 (Box-folder 92: 7)
    - No. 51, pp. 1162-1180 (Box-folder 92: 8)
    - No. 52, pp. 1181-1201 (Box-folder 92: 9)
    - No. 53, pp. 1202-1216 (Box-folder 92: 10)
    - No. 54, pp. 1217-1239 (Box-folder 92: 11)
    - No. 55, pp. 1240-1264 (Box-folder 92: 12)
    - No. 56, pp. 1265-1297 (Box-folder 92: 13)
    - No. 57, pp. 1298-1310 (Box-folder 92: 14)
    - No. 58, pp. 1311-1329 (Box-folder 92: 15)
    - No. 59, pp. 1330-1346 (Box-folder 92: 16)
    - No. 60, pp. 1347-1357 (Box-folder 92: 17)
    - No. 61, pp. 1358-1370 (Box-folder 92: 18)
    - No. 62, pp. 1371-1385 (Box-folder 92: 19)
    - No. 63, pp. 1386-1398 (Box-folder 92: 20)
    - No. 64, pp. 1399-1409 (Box-folder 92: 21)
    - No. 65, pp. 1410-1429 (Box-folder 92: 22)
    - No. 66, pp. 1430-1443 (Box-folder 92: 23)
    - No. 67, pp. 1444-1459 (Box-folder 92: 24)
    - No. 68, pp. 1460-1481 (Box-folder 92: 25)
    - No. 69, pp. 1482-1491 (Box-folder 92: 26)
    - No. 70, pp. 1492-1508 (Box-folder 92: 27)
    - No. 71, pp. 1509-1528 (Box-folder 92: 28)
    - No. 72, pp. 1529-1547 (Box-folder 92: 29)
    - No. 73, pp. 1548-1554 (Box-folder 92: 30)
    - No. 74, pp. 1555-1571 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - No. 75, pp. 1572-1589 (Box-folder 93: 2)
    - No. 76, pp. 1590-1594 (Box-folder 93: 3)
    - No. 77, pp. 1595-1616 (Box-folder 93: 4)
    - No. 78, pp. 1617-1643 (Box-folder 93: 5)
    - No. 79, pp. 1644-1662 (Box-folder 93: 6)
    - No. 80, pp. 1663-1680 (Box-folder 93: 7)
    - No. 81, pp. 1681-1692 (Box-folder 93: 8)
    - No. 82, pp. 1693-1703 (Box-folder 93: 9)
    - No. 83, pp. 1704-1716 (Box-folder 93: 10)
    - No. 84, pp. 1717-1730 (Box-folder 93: 11)
    - No. 85, pp. 1731-1754 (Box-folder 93: 12)
    - No. 86, pp. 1755-1771 (Box-folder 93: 13)
    - No. 87, pp. 1772-1785 (Box-folder 93: 14)
    - No. 88, pp. 1786-1805 (Box-folder 93: 15)
    - No. 89, pp. 1806-1823 (Box-folder 93: 16)
    - No. 90, pp. 1824-1847 (Box-folder 93: 17)
    - No. 91, pp. 1848-1871 (Box-folder 93: 18)
    - No. 92, pp. 1872-1891 (Box-folder 93: 19)
    - No. 93, pp. 1892-1912 (Box-folder 93: 20)
    - No. 94, pp. 1913-1938 (Box-folder 93: 21)
    - No. 95, pp. 1939-1956 (Box-folder 93: 22)
    - No. 96, pp. 1957-1978 (Box-folder 93: 23)
  - Unnumbered dated originals
    - 1936 (Box-folder 93: 24)
    - 1941(?) (Box-folder 93: 25)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 94: 1)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 94: 2)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 94: 3)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 94: 4)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 94: 5-6)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 94: 7)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 94: 8-9)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 94: 10)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 94: 11)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 94: 12)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 94: 13)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 94: 14)
    - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 94: 15)
- Newspaper Columns, 1967-1970
  Articles for "Sunday Thoughts" and "Reflections," listed chronologically, and letters to the editor for "Reflections," listed at the end.
  - "Sunday Thoughts," San Francisco Examiner and Chronicle, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - "Reflections," nationally syndicated column
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 95: 2)
    - Notes for articles (Box-folder 95: 3)
    - List of articles (Box-folder 95: 4)
    - "Freedom and Power,", undated (Box-folder 95: 5)
    - "Reflections on Juveniles,", undated (Box-folder 95: 6)
    - "The Workingman in Czechoslovakia,", undated (Box-folder 95: 7)
    - "The Negro Needs Genuine Heroes – Not Slogan-Slingers,", 1967 (Box-folder 95: 8)
    - "Fulfillment of the Undesirables,", 1968 January 14 (Box-folder 95: 9)
    - "Automation – The New Garden of Eden?,", 1968 January 28 (Box-folder 95: 10)
      Typescript and proofs
    - "Youth Is a Time of Ferment,", 1968 February 11 (Box-folder 95: 11)
    - "I Answer Some Mail,", 1968 February 18 (Box-folder 95: 12)
    - "The Rude Awakening of Asia,", 1968 March 3 (Box-folder 95: 13)
    - "Anyone Can Write a Column like This,", 1968 March 10 (Box-folder 95: 14)
    - "The Occident – Mystery of the World,", 1968 March 17 (Box-folder 95: 15)
    - "A Kind Word for the Intellectual,", 1968 March 24 (Box-folder 95: 16)
    - "A Century of Juveniles,", 1968 March 31 (Box-folder 95: 17)
    - "A Worker Looks at Management,", 1968 April 7 (Box-folder 95: 18)
    - "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow,", 1968 April 14 (Box-folder 95: 19)
    - "The Pride and the Greatness,", 1968 April 21 (Box-folder 95: 20)
    - "The Playful Mood,", 1968 April 29 (Box-folder 95: 21)
    - "The Disease of Rioting,", 1968 May 5 (Box-folder 95: 22)
      Holograph, typescript, and printed copy
    - "Europeans Are Being Americanized and Vice Versa,", 1968 May 12 (Box-folder 95: 23)
    - "Nature Is for the Birds,", 1968 May 19 (Box-folder 95: 24)
    - "Israel Stands Alone,", 1968 May 26 (Box-folder 95: 25)
    - "The Negro's Vicious Circle,", 1968 June 2 (Box-folder 95: 26)
    - "Kids and Men on Campus,", 1968 June 9 (Box-folder 95: 27)
    - "The Damnation of the Young,", 1968 June 16 (Box-folder 95: 28)
    - "Readiness to Work,", 1968 June 23 (Box-folder 95: 29)
    - "The Lessons of French Revolt,", 1968 June 30 (Box-folder 95: 30)